export const chapter = "Chapter - 2: North India in Early Medieval Period ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "During which two time periods is the medieval period divided?",
        optionA: "5th to 10th century and 11th to 15th century",
        optionB: "8th to 12th century and 13th to 18th century",
        optionC: "6th to 9th century and 10th to 14th century",
        correctAnswer: "b) 8th to 12th century and 13th to 18th century",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What does the word 'Rajput' likely mean, according to the text?",
        optionA: "Descendant of a priest",
        optionB: "Son of a king",
        optionC: "Warrior of the land",
        correctAnswer: "b) Son of a king",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which Rajput clan ruled over Delhi during the early medieval period?",
        optionA: "Chauhans",
        optionB: "Solankis",
        optionC: "Tomars",
        correctAnswer: "c) Tomars",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who was the famous Rajput ruler known for his battles against Muhammad Ghori?",
        optionA: "King Bhoja",
        optionB: "Prithviraj Chauhan",
        optionC: "Raja Bhoj",
        correctAnswer: "b) Prithviraj Chauhan",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which dynasty struggled for control over Kannauj in North India?",
        optionA: "Palas",
        optionB: "Pratiharas",
        optionC: "Rashtrakutas",
        correctAnswer: "b) Pratiharas",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which language remained the main language of the Brahmins and other high-caste people during the early medieval period?",
        optionA: "Gujarati",
        optionB: "Sanskrit",
        optionC: "Bengali",
        correctAnswer: "b) Sanskrit",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who was the ambitious ruler of Ghazni who invaded India multiple times?",
        optionA: "Muhammad Bin Qasim",
        optionB: "Mahmud of Ghazni",
        optionC: "Muhammad Ghori",
        correctAnswer: "b) Mahmud of Ghazni",
      },
      {
        question: "What important work did AI-Beruni write about India?",
        optionA: "Shahnama",
        optionB: "Kitab-ul-Hind",
        optionC: "Gita Govinda",
        correctAnswer: "b) Kitab-ul-Hind",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the main reason for the defeat of the Rajputs in their battles against the Turks, as mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "Lack of loyalty to their respective kingdoms",
        optionB: "Inferior weaponry and strategies",
        optionC: "Non-participation of the Kshatriyas",
        correctAnswer: "a) Lack of loyalty to their respective kingdoms",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which ruler became the first Turk ruler of Delhi after Muhammad Ghori's death?",
        optionA: "Prithviraj Chauhan",
        optionB: "Qutb-ud-din Aibak",
        optionC: "Vikramaditya II",
        correctAnswer: "b) Qutb-ud-din Aibak",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "During the early medieval period, several new dynasties rose in North India, including the ___________, the Pratiharas, the Palas, and the Rashtrakutas.",
        options: ["Rajputs", "Mughals", "Marathas"],
        correctAnswer: "Rajputs",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Rajputs are considered a martial race, claiming to be the descendants of the ___________.",
        options: ["Brahmins", "Kshatriyas", "Vaishyas"],
        correctAnswer: "Kshatriyas",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Prithviraj Chauhan was a legendary Chahamanas ruler who defeated Mohammad Ghori in the battle of Tarain in __________.",
        options: ["1190 AD", "1191 AD", "1192 AD"],
        correctAnswer: "1191 AD",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The struggle for control over Kannauj among the Palas, Pratiharas, and Rashtrakutas is known as the ___________ struggle.",
        options: ["Triangular", "Tripartite", "Trilateral"],
        correctAnswer: "Tripartite",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The medieval period was a time of increased trade, resulting in the emergence of languages like ___________ in Europe.",
        options: ["Latin", "Gujarati", "Bengali"],
        correctAnswer: "Bengali",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Mahmud of Ghazni invaded India multiple times in the 11th century and is known for targeting prosperous Indian cities and temples, such as those in Mathura, Kannauj, and ___________.",
        options: ["Delhi", "Somnath", "Ayodhya"],
        correctAnswer: "Somnath",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The battle between Muhammad Ghori and Prithviraj Chauhan that marked the beginning of Muslim rule in India is known as the battle of ___________.",
        options: ["Panipat", "Tarain", "Buxar"],
        correctAnswer: "Tarain",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The frequent divisions among the Rajput rulers and their lack of unity led to their defeat due to the element of ___________ used by the invaders.",
        options: ["Surprise", "Courage", "Strategy"],
        correctAnswer: "Surprise",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Mughal emperor who had to grant Diwani rights of Bengal, Bihar, and Orissa to the British East India Company was ___________.",
        options: ["Akbar", "Shah Jahan", "Shah Alam II"],
        correctAnswer: "Shah Alam II",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The system of ___________ was brought to an end in 1772 by Warren Hastings, the Governor of Bengal.",
        options: ["Dual administration", "Monopoly trading", "Colonial rule"],
        correctAnswer: "Dual administration",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "Prithviraj Chauhan defeated Mohammad Ghori in the battle of Tarain in 1191 AD.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "The Rajputs were known to be descendents of the Kshatriyas.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The medieval period saw the emergence of languages like Latin, Gujarati, and Bengali in Europe.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Mahmud of Ghazni plundered the temples in Mathura, Kannauj, and Ayodhya.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Battle of Tarain marked the beginning of direct Muslim rule in India.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The frequent divisions among the Rajput rulers and their lack of unity contributed to their defeat in battles.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Shah Alam II granted Diwani rights of Bengal, Bihar, and Orissa to the British East India Company.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Warren Hastings, the Governor of Bengal, ended the system of colonial rule in 1772.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Portuguese enjoyed a cartel of trade in India during the sixteenth century.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Economic exploitation by the British East India Company in Bengal resulted in a financial crisis but brought significant benefits to the population.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
